We use statistics in a lot of different ways in data science.
我們使用統計學在很多不同的方式在數據科學裡。
In this lecture, I want to refresh your knowledge of hypothesis testing,
在這堂課中，我想更新您對假設檢定(hypothesis testing)的認識，
which is a core data analysis activity behind experimentation.
這是實驗背後的核心數據分析活動。
We're starting to see experimentation used more and more commonly
我們開始看到使用實驗越來越普遍
outside of academic scientific, and in day to day business environments.
在學術科學之外，以及在日常業務環境中。
Part of the reason for this is the rise of big data and web commerce.
部分原因是，大數據(big data)和電子商務的興起。
It's now easy to change your digital storefront and
現在您可以容易的更改數位店面，
deliver a different experience to some of your customers, and
並為您的某些客戶提供不同的體驗，
then see how those customer actions might differ from one another.
然後查看這些客戶反應可能會如何彼此不同。
For instance, if you sell books, you might want to have one condition where the cover
例如，如果您銷售圖書，您可能希望有一個情況，其中該
of the book is featured on the web page and
圖書的封面在網頁上突出顯示，
another condition where the focus is on the author and the reviews of the book.
另一個情況是焦點在作者和該書的評論。
This is often called A/B testing.
這通常被稱為A/B測試。
And while it's not unique to this time in history, it's now becoming so common that
雖然這在歷史上並不是獨一無二的，但現在變得越來越普遍，
if you're using a website, you are undoubtedly part of an A/B test somewhere.
如果你使用的是一個網站，那麼你無疑是A/B測試的一部分。
This raises some interesting ethical questions and I've added a reading to
這就引起了一些有趣的道德問題，我已經添加到閱讀
the course resources and I would like to encourage you to check it out and
課程資源，我想鼓勵你去看看，
join in the discussion, but let's refocus back on statistics.
參加討論，但讓我們重新回到統計上。
A hypothesis is a statement that we can test.
假設(Hypothesis)，是我們可以測試的聲明。
I'll pull an example from my own research of educational technology and
我舉一個例子，從我自己的研究領域的教育技術和
learning analytics.
學習分析。
Let's say that we have an expectation that when a new course is launched on a MOOC
假設我們有一個期待，當新課程在MOOC平台上推出時，
platform, the keenest students find out about it and all flock to it.
最敏銳的學生就會發現了，並且都會湧向它。
Thus, we might expect that those students who sign up quite quickly after
因此，我們可能會想，那些很快報名的學生
the course is launched with higher performance than those
當課程開始時，將會有更高的表現，比那些
students who signed up after the MOOC has been around for a while.
MOOC課程已經存在一段時間之後報名的的學生。
In this example, we have samples from two different groups which we want to compare.
在此示例中，我們有我們想要比較的兩個不同組的樣本。
The early sign ups and the late sign ups.
早期註冊和晚期註冊。
When we do hypothesis testing, we hold out that our hypothesis as the alternative and
當我們進行假設檢測時，我們堅持認為我們的假設是對立(alternative)假設，
we create a second hypothesis called the null hypothesis,
我們創建了一個稱為零假設(null hypothesis)的第二個假設，
which in this case would be that there is no difference between groups.
在這零假設情況下，這兩組之間沒有區別。
We then examine the groups to determine whether this null hypothesis is
然後我們檢查這兩組以確定這個零假設
true or not.
真實與否。
If we find that there is a difference between groups,
如果我們發現群體之間存在差異，
then we can reject the null hypothesis and we accept our alternative.
那麼我們可以拋棄零假設，而接受我們的對立假設
There are subtleties in this description.
在這個描述中有微妙之處。
We aren't saying that our hypothesis is true per se, but
我們不是說我們的假設是對的，而
we're saying that there's evidence against the null hypothesis.
我們說的是有證據反對零(null)假設。
So, we're more confident in our alternative hypothesis.
所以，我們對我們的對立(alternative)假設更有信心。
Let's see an example of this.
我們來看個例子
We can load a file called grids.csv.
我們可以加載一個名為grade.csv的文件。
If we take a look at the data frame inside,
如果我們在裡面看看DataFrame，
we see we have six different assignments.
我們看到我們有六個不同的作業，
Each with a submission time and
每個作業都有一個提交時間。
it looks like there just under 3,000 entries in this data file.
而且這個數據文件中似乎3,000項以下。
For the purpose of this lecture, let's segment this population in to two pieces.
為了這講座的目的，我們把這個群體分成兩部分。
Those who finish the first assignment by the end of December 2015 and
那些在2015年12月底之前完成第一個作業的人
those who finish it sometimes after that.
和那些在那段時間之後完成的人。
I just made this date up and it gives us two data frames,
我編造了這個日期，它給了我們兩個DataFrames，
which are roughly the same size.
大致是大小相同的。
As you've seen, the pandas data frame object has a variety of statistical
如您所見，pandas DataFrame物件有各種各樣的統計
functions associated with it.
函數與之相關聯。
If we call the mean function directly on the data frame,
如果我們直接在DataFrame上調用平均值(mean)函數，
we see that each of the means for the assignments are calculated.
那麼我們可以看到每個平均值在每個作業都被計算出來。
Note that the date time values are ignored as panda's knows this isn't a number,
請注意，datetime值將被忽略，Pandas都知道這不是一個數字，
but an object type.
而是一個物件類型。
If we look at the mean values for the late data frame as well,
如果我們看看late DataFrame的平均值
we get surprisingly similar numbers.
，我們會得到驚人的相似數字。
There are slight differences, though.
雖然有微小的差異。
It looks like the end of the six assignments,
它看起來像六個作業的結束，
the early users are doing better by about a percentage point.
早期的學生做的好一點，大概一個百分點。
So, is this enough to go ahead and make some interventions to actually try and
那麼，這是否足以繼續下去，做一些干預，以實際的方式來嘗試和
change something in the way we teach?
改變一些東西在我們的授課的方式？
When doing hypothesis testing, we have to choose a significance level as a threshold
在進行假設檢驗時，我們必須選擇一個顯著(significance)程度(level)作為門檻，
for how much of a chance we're willing to accept.
表示多少或然性我們願意接受。
This significance level is typically called alpha.
這個顯著程度通常稱為alpha(α)。
It can vary greatly, depending on what you're going to do with the result and
它可能會差別很大，這取決於你的結果將要拿來做什麼和
the amount of noise you expect in your data.
數據中你預期的雜訊量。
For instance, in social sciences research, a value of 0.05 or
例如，在社會科學研究中，通常使用0.05或
0.01 is often used, which indicates a tolerance for
0.01的值，這表明寬限在
a probability of between 5% and 1% of chance.
概率5％到1％的或然性之間。
In a physics experiment where the conditions are much more controlled and
在物理實驗中，條件受到更多的控制，
thus, the burden of proof is much higher, you might expect to see alpha
因此，舉證責任要高得多，您可能預期看到alpha
levels of 10 to the negative 5 or 100,000th of a percentage.
層級到十的負五次方，或是十萬分之一。
You can think of the significance level from the perspective of interventions as
你也可以從干預觀點來想顯著程度，
well and this is something I run into regularly with my research.
這是我經常在我的研究中遇到的問題。
What am I going to do when I find out that two student populations are different?
我該怎麼辦時，我發現兩個學生群體是不同的？
For instance, if I'm going to send an email nudge to encourage students to
例如，如果我要發送一個輕推的電子郵件來鼓勵學生
continue working on their homework, that's a pretty low-cost intervention.
繼續努力作作業，那是一個非常低成本的干預。
Emails are cheap and while I certainly don't want to annoy students,
電子郵件很便宜，而我當然不想惹惱學生，
one extra email isn't going to ruin their day.
一個額外的電子郵件不會破壞他們的一天。
But what if the intervention is a little more involved,
但是，如果干預是有點要更多功夫，
like having our tutorial assistant followup with a student via phone?
好比我們助教與學生通過電話隨訪？
This is all of a sudden much more expensive for both the institution and for
這突然變得更加昂貴對於機構和
the student.
學生
So, I might want to ensure a higher burden of proof.
所以，我可能想需要確保更高的舉證責任。
So the threshold you set for
所以你設置的門檻
alpha depends on what you might do with the result, as well.
alpha取決於你的結果將要拿來做什麼。
For this example, let's use a threshold of 0.05 for our alpha or 5%.
對於這個例子，我們使用一個0.05的門檻作為我們的alpha，或5％。
Now, how do we actually test whether these means are different in Python?
現在，我們怎麼實際上來測試這些平均值是否在Python中不同？
The SciPy library contains a number of different statistical tests and
SciPy程式庫包含許多不同的統計測試，並且
forms a basis for hypothesis testing in Python.
構成了Python中假設檢定的基礎。
A T test is one way to compare the means of two different populations.
t-test是比較兩種不同種群的平均值(mean)的一種方式。
In the SciPy library, the T test end function will
在SciPy程式庫中，ttest_ind函數將
compare two independent samples to see if they have different means.
比較兩個獨立的樣本，看看它們是否有不同的平均值(mean)。
I'm not going to go into the details of any of this statistical test here.
我不會在這裡進行任何這種統計測試的細節，
But instead, we'd recommend that you check out the Wikipedia page on particular test
但是我們建議您查看維基百科頁面上的特定測試，
or consider taking a full statistics course if this is unfamiliar to you.
或考慮上一個完整的統計學課程，如果這是你不熟悉的。
But I do want to note that most statistical tests expect that
但是我想要注意的是，大多數統計測試都需要
the data conforms to a certain distribution, a shape.
數據符合一定的分佈形狀。
So, you shouldn't apply such tests blindly and should investigate your data first.
所以你不應該盲目地應用這些測試，首先要調查你的數據。
If we want to compare the assignment grades for
如果我們想要比較作業的分數
the first assignment between the two populations, we could generate a T test
在這兩個群體之間的第一個作業，我們可以產生t-test
by passing these two series into the T test in function.
將這兩個系列傳遞給ttest_ind函數。
The result is a two with a test statistic and a p-value.
結果是測試統計量(t-statistic)和p值(p-value)的元組(tuple)。
The p-value here is much larger than our 0.05.
此處的p值是遠遠大於我們的0.05。
So we cannot reject the null hypothesis,
所以我們不能拋棄null假設，
which is that the two populations are the same.
null假設就是說這兩個群體是一樣的。
In more late terms, we would say that there's
在更專業術語，我們會說
no statistically significant difference between these two sample means.
沒有統計學上的顯著差異，在這兩個樣本的平均值。
Let's check with assignment two grade.
讓我們檢查第二個作業分數。
No, that's much larger than 0.052.
不，這也是遠遠大於0.05。
How about with assignment three?
作業三怎麼樣呢？
Well, that's much closer, but still beyond our threshold value.
這更接近了，但仍然超出我們的門檻。
It's important to stop here and talk about serious process from with how we're
重要的是要停下來，談論嚴重的過程問題，我們如何處理
handling this investigation of the difference between these two populations.
這兩個群體之間差異的調查。
When we set the alpha to be 0.05, we're saying that we expect it that there
當我們將alpha設置為0.05時，我們說我們期望它
will be positive result, 5% of the time just to the chance.
會有正面結果，5％的時候純粹因為偶然機會。
As we run more and more T tests, we're more likely to find a positive result
隨著我們運行越來越多的t-test，我們更有可能找到一個正面的結果，
just because of the number of T tests we have run.
只是因為我們運行的t-test的數量。
When a data scientist run many tests in this way, it's called p-hacking or
當數據科學家以這種方式進行許多測試時，它被稱為p-hacking或
dredging and it's a serious methodological issue.
疏浚(dredging)，這是一個嚴重的方法問題。
P-hacking results in spurious correlations instead of generalizable results.
P-hacking導致虛假的相關性，而不是一般化的結果。
There are a couple of different ways you can deal with p-hacking.
有幾種不同的方式來處理p-hacking。
The first is called the Bonferroni correction.
第一個被稱為Bonferroni校正。
In this case, you simply tighten your alpha value,
在這種情況下，您只需緊縮您的Alpha值，
the threshold of significance based on the number of tests you're running.
即顯著性的門檻，按照您運行的測試次數。
So if you choose 0.05 with 1 test, you want to run 3 test,
所以如果你選擇了0.05在一個測試，而你想運行3個測試，
you reduce alpha by multiplying 0.05 by one-third to get a new value of 0.01 sub.
你減少alpha，用0.05乘三分之一，得到一個新的值0.01多
I personally find this approach to be very conservative.
我個人覺得這個做法非常保守。
Another option is to hold out some of your data for
另一個選擇是，保留您的一些數據進行
testing to see how generizable your result is.
測試，以了解您的結果有多一般化。
In this case, we might take half of our data for
在這種情況下，我們可能會採用一半我們的數據
each of the two data frames, run our T test with that.
在每個DataFrames，用這一半運行我們的t-test，
Form specific hypothesis based on the result of these tests,
建立具體的假設，基於這些測試的結果，
then run very limited tests on the rest of the data.
然後用其餘的數據，運行非常有限的測試。
This method is actually heavily used in machine learning when
這種方法實際上被大量地用於機器學習，
building predictive models where it's called cross fold validation and
當構建預測模型時，它稱為交叉(cross fold)驗證(validation)，
you'll learn more about this in third course in this specialization.
您將在此專業化的第三課程中更多地了解這一點。
A final method which has come about is the pre-registration of your experiment.
最後一種方法來的是，預先登記你的實驗。
In this step, you would outline what you expect to find and why, and
在此步驟中，您將概述您期望找到的內容以及為什麼，
describe the test that would backup a positive proof of this.
並描述此測試，它將提供一個積極的證明。
You register it with a third party, in academic circles, this is often a journal
您與第三方註冊，在學術界這通常是一個刊物。
who determines whether it's a reasonable test or rather not.
他們決定要運行的測試是否合理。
You then run your study and report the results,
你然後運行你的研究和報告它的結果，
regardless as to whether they were positive or not.
無論它們是否是肯定的。
Here, there is a larger burden on connecting to existing theory since
在這裡有一個更大的負擔來連接到現有的理論，
you need to convince reviewers that the experiment is likely to test
因為你需要說服審閱者，實驗非常可能完全的測試了
fully a given hypothesis.
你給定的假設。
In this lecture,
在這堂課，
we've discussed just some of the basics of hypothesis testing in Python.
我們只是討論了一些在Python中基本的假設測試。
I introduced you to the SciPy library, which you can use for T testing.
我向您介紹了SciPy程式庫，您可以用它來進行t-test。
We've discussed some of the practical issues which arise from looking for
我們討論了一些實際的問題，源自於尋找
statistical significance.
在統計學上來講的顯著性。
There's much more to learn about hypothesis testing.
還有更多假設測試要學習。
For instance, there are different tests used,
例如，不同的測試方法，
depending on the shape of your data and different ways to report
取決於數據的形狀，以及不同的方法報告結果，
results instead of just p-values such as confidence intervals.
而不僅僅是p-value，例如置信區間(confidence interval)。
But I hope this gives you a start to comparing the means of two
但是，我希望這可以讓您開始比較平均值在兩個
different populations, which is a common task for data scientists and
不同群體，對於數據科學家來說是一項常見的任務，
we'll followup some of this work in the second course in this series.
我們將在本系列的第二個課程中跟進一些這方面的工作。
This lecture also completes the lectures for
這堂課還完成了第一門的課程
the first course in the Applied Data Science with Python Specialization.
在Python專業化應用數據科學。
We've covered the basics of Python programming,
我們已經涵蓋基本的Python程式設計，
some more advanced features like maps, lambdas and miscomprehensions.
一些更高級的功能如map、lambda和列表(list)推導。
How to read and manipulate data using the panda's library, including querying,
如何使用Pandas程式庫讀取和操作數據，包括查詢，
joining, grouping and processing of data frames and the creation of pivot tables.
加入，分組和處理DataFrames以及建立樞紐分析表(pivot table)。
And now we've talked a little bit about statistics in Python and
現在我們已經討論了一些在Python中的統計學，
dug deeper into the Num-Py and SciPy toolkit.
並深入到了NumPy和SciPy 工具庫中。
In the next course, we'll dig into plotting and charting of data.
在接下來的課程中，我們將討論數據的繪圖和圖表。
Dealing a bit more with statistics and how we present data to others, and
使用更多統計數據，以及我們如何向他人呈現數據，
how we build a compelling story for the data we have.
以及我們如何用我們的數據建立一個令人信服的故事。
I'll see you then.
我們下回再見。